[Applause]
hello viewers welcome back to my YouTube
channel
today in this course we are going to see
all about Azure open AI exercises okay
so we are going to perform some of the
exercises which are on generative AI
and the offerings on Azure cloud from
openai all the open AI Services which
are available on azure
we are going to do some Hands-On on that
for that I have also created Azure
subscription using my account this month
you can use this email if you have any
queries to write it for me so let's
proceed
so in this code first handphone is
exploring generative AI with being
copied
so let's open this in a new tab
and move to this new tab
here
we'll go through this
whole course for Hands-On write-up given
here on this page one bye
so before you start you need a personal
Microsoft account
if you do not have one go to sign up
live.com to sign up and create a
personal account which I already have
which is surprised it 08
which I already have so I'll be using
this account
okay
now open bing.com and sign in with your
personal Microsoft account
so let me open this in a new tab
okay
I've opened it and I have also signed in
using that same account
right
so that's the first thing I have done
so I have already signed
okay
if you don't know how to sign in
you will see this type of Icon where if
you are signed out
you can click on sign in button which
will be showing here and then give all
the Account Details like email ID and
password and sign in using Microsoft
Live account
okay and for us creating that live
account we can go to this site and
create one
now moving
so once you sign in using your work or
school account you'll see a slightly
different user experience then what I
see as a personal account so this is my
personal Microsoft
black account but you'll see a different
uh UI
so that's for being Enterprise chat okay
because it's related to your work and
explore
so it will be an Enterprise check
next
select chat from the menu at the top of
the screen
chat brings you to bring for pilot okay
let's chat
and it is taking me to
this chat interface being chat interview
next
what this means is that unlike search
alone like normally what we do in Google
search or Bing search
we have some search bar we click some
words here some points here and then
we just hit enter or click on search
button and we can search that
online using the Bing or Google search
in this or any other searching
but here
unlike any search engine
Bing co-pilot can put together new
responses based on natural language
modeling
so it works on a NLP or natural language
processing
which gives responses similar to what a
human
normally uh
speaks or relation right so that kind of
uh language
these AIS
artificial intelligence built into the
Bing browser Bing chat it can provide
and it's basically using Bing
is using chat GPT fourth version right
we have other old versions like charity
3.5 as well
but here Bing chat is using chat GPT 4
okay
now towards the bottom of the screen
you'll see a window ask me anything
let me keep these steps side by side so
that way we'll be able to see it more
properly
okay so this is our chat interface and
here it is saying ask me anything
right
if you enter the prompts into the window
beam copilot uses the entire
conversation ready to return the sponsor
so let's try one thing
so in the prompt or here in the ask me
anything
I am going to write this one what are
the three pros and cons of traveling in
a winter in the winter
I can also speak using this microphone
or I can type the whole thing here
let me just speak it in the microphone
I'll allow microphone
what are the three pros and cons of
traveling in the winter
so this is the prompt I have given
searching for pros and cons of traveling
in the winter traveling in Winter has
its own set of advantages and
disadvantages here are some of the pros
and cons of traveling in Winter Pros
cheaper prices winter is considered
Enough season for travel which means
that many airlines hotels enter
operators offer discounts to attract
more customers fewer crowds since winter
is not a popular time to travel there
are fewer tourists at popular
destinations this means that you can
enjoy the sights and sounds without
having to deal with large crowds winter
sports if you're a fan of winter sports
like skiing snowboarding or ice skating
then traveling in winter is perfect for
you
many scale Resorts offer great deals
during the winter months cons
bad weather winter weather can be
unpredictable and harsh which can led to
flight cancellations delays and other
travel disruptions limited daylight
during the winter months the days are
shorter which means that you have less
time to explore your destination
seasonal closures some attractions and
activities may be closed during the
winter months due to weather conditions
or seasonal closures I hope
so once you click to stop the readout
then it will stop in between whatever it
is reading out all right so all this
response that you get it's very
customized or bulleted point a very
structured way right you can see the
response with all the headings mentioned
here pros and cons and each bullet
points have subheadings as well right
but that's what we are going to see as a
chat response now here
if I just
give find me three pros right I'll copy
this and paste it here
and just send it or submit it
okay so it will give me the response
of pros of traveling inventor well I
gave only these three
or four words right find me three more
Pros right but
chat uh this chat interface or chat GPT
already knows about the context in which
I am taught right which is about the
winter
pros and cons winter season or traveling
in the winter season right so that's the
context like what are the pros and cons
of traveling in the winter
so this is the actual context traveling
in Wind okay and if I'm asking for pros
so it is already
giving me these three pros of
traveling in winter
so it already knows about the conference
now if I'll just write
this one okay
so let me just use my microphone to give
this prompt
what are three places I can go to find
fewer crowds
searching for places to travel in winter
with fewer crowd
I stopped playing this but I can get the
response still right so readout is
stopped but the response is
coming from chat Equity AI so we get
this three uh results a responses about
the places where we can travel and we'll
have fewer Cloud crowds okay
Italy Saint Lucia and Mount Fiji or PC
in Japan
all these options we are getting right
so notice that the Bingo pilot is able
to give a related response okay
it can drop earlier memories of the
conversation
that's as it continue as a result the
responses you get may not be directly
related to the traveling
this is largely due to the Token input
limitation when chat remembers earlier
parts of the conversation or the context
of the conversation it is because it has
saved a certain amount of tokens from
the conversation
earlier we gave
this prompt right
pros and cons of traveling it already
got the context by that query from that
query yes so it already knows about the
content okay
as new tokens are introduced by your new
prompt and responses Chat Me Network
so as we go further and give some varied
prompts or different prompts which is
different than
this context existing contract then the
older tokens will
get removed and newer tokens
based on our neighbor prompts and topics
that we are writing here it will be
saved within chat GPT
so it will remember the new tokens
basically and reply based on the newer
token the new topic button next to the
chat window is useful being co-pilot to
clear the previous conversion so if you
click on the new topic it will omit or
remove all the folder
uh tokens basically and it will start a
new topic with a
without any problems
so this will be very new topic now we
can also give prompts like create an
image of an elephant eating a hamburger
so this will generate
a new
images okay using Dali okay Dali's
generative AI for image generation right
so it will generate images based on the
text prompt that we will give
so let's give this from instead I will
give a different prompt and let's see
what happens
create an image of a dog eating a
hamburger
searching for dog
dog eating hamburger right
so that's my problem and here you can
see the response which is almost look
like
uh which is looking very real like a dog
is eating a hamburger right it's
generated by Dali
now if you notice the responses may look
similar but not the same
okay these are looking very similar but
all these images are different
maybe from side view from
top or or front view like that okay
so these are very different
responsive
image responsible
so in the response there is a touch at
the bottom that means powered by darling
so consider how Dali is based on large
language model as your natural language
input generates image so Dali is nothing
but uh
image generation AI or artificial
intelligence
which is trained on
so many images
to generate realistic images based on
our text
so whatever the text prompt we are given
like dog eating hamburger
it is trying to take that text as tokens
and then based on the tokens trying to
identify
context like hamburger
dog and the process is about 80.
or
images which are almost similar but not
the same and
considering this talk so a dog eating
handle
now return to bingo pilot chat by
clicking on the Microsoft Bing icon on
the top right corner of the screen
okay
baby click on this so this opens up the
small side window right now let's see an
example of fourth generation and
translate type in a prompt use
python to create a list okay
just give this problem
and paste it here
and submit it
use Python to create a list
and here you can see some examples
related to python code where it's trying
to
create an empty list
and then it's time to add
three numbers one two and three within
that list and then here we can see the
output if we print the list
okay
so
there is a shortcut way like that my
list equal to
within this Square braces you put all
the list items like one two and three
numbers so this is how chat repeat is
also able to give us python codes right
now type in the prompt translate that
into shisha
so the current Port that we have in the
python we want it to be converted to a C
sharp based port
so we'll just click or give the prompt
translate that into C sharp
okay
and then that code will be translated
into a C sharp based coding where we are
creating a new list which is following a
C sharp syntax right then we are adding
three
numbers one two and three and then we
are using console.writeline
to print that list of items okay one by
one using four original
okay and you're creating over the
list items okay
so this is the result or we can create
a new list by hardboarding the values
like one to n directly
okay
so both ways we can create
a list
now
here is a bonus form what are the three
examples of generative AI helping people
okay
so let's do that
we'll copy this
okay and let's put here in this chat
window I'll close this you can always
call this chat window from here or you
can go to
this vendor and then you can put your
prompt here
let me submit this
so these are the examples of
generative AI helping people like
healthcare accessibility product
development
boarding that would be more
we ask only three so it's giving three
responses so that's about
exploring the generative AI with bank so
that's all for now in the next section
we'll explore Azure open AI Services
okay and for that we are going to use or
azure
uh Cloud portal
please like share and subscribe to my
channel
and also comment below if you found this
video interesting thank you bye bye
foreign
[Music]